<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Android Tourism Application</string>
    <string name="register"><u>Register</u></string>
    <string name="Login">Login</string>
    <string name="Login2"><u>Login</u></string>
    <string name="skip"><u>Skip</u></string>
    <string name="logo">Logo</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="signup">Sign-Up</string>
    <string name="location">location</string>
    <string name="location_name">Location Name</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>



    <string name="map_api">AIzaSyBEhL9Yur-AoiMjWbi4oKDNLXhJ38Y8c2c</string>


    <string name="desc">Dunnottar Castle is a ruined medieval fortress located upon a rocky headland on the northeastern coast of Scotland, about 2 miles south of Stonehaven. \n \n The surviving buildings are largely of the 15th and 16th centuries, but the site is believed to have been fortified in the Early Middle Ages. \n \n   Dunnottar has played a prominent role in the history of Scotland through to the 18th-century Jacobite risings because of its strategic location and defensive strength.  \n \n  Dunnottar is best known as the place where the Honours of Scotland, the Scottish crown jewels, were hidden from Oliver Cromwell\'s invading army in the 17th century. The property of the Keiths from the 14th century, and the seat of the Earl Marischal, Dunnottar declined after the last Earl forfeited his titles by taking part in the Jacobite rebellion of 1715. The ruins of the castle are surrounded by steep cliffs that drop to the North Sea, 160 feet below.  \n \n  A narrow strip of land joins the headland to the mainland, along which a steep path leads up to the gatehouse. The various buildings within the castle include the 14th-century tower house as well as the 16th-century palace."</string>
    <string name="PAPdesc">The unbelievable stone cairn, which is one of eleven to be found on the estate, stands like a miniature version of those more famous pyramids built in Ancient Egypt. \n \n Erected by Queen Victoria, it was created in memory of her husband Prince Albert after his death in 1861, aged just 42. The huge four-sided structure was built using granite and is 41 feet by 41 feet at the base. A plaque on the unique monument reads: "To the beloved memory of Albert, the great and good prince and consort. Erected by his broken-hearted widow Victoria." \n \n The Queen also erected other cairns on the estate that she loved, with several built to commemorate the marriages of many of her children such as Beatrice, Helena and Leopold. Around the same area you\'ll also find the Crathie Kirk and a statue to John Brown, Queen Victoria\'s loyal servant of many years until his death in 1883 - with an inscription that describes him as a "friend more than a servant". \n \n  The cairns can be accessed via the Crathie car park. An enjoyable walk, it\'s worth checking ahead to ensure the estate is open to visitors.</string>

    <string name="linlithgow_palace">Linlithgow Palace</string>
    <string name="LINdesc">A royal manor existed on the site in the 12th century. It was replaced by a fortification known as "the Peel" built in the 14th century by occupying English forces under Edward I. \n \n The site of the manor made it an ideal military base for securing the supply routes between Edinburgh Castle and Stirling Castle. The English fort was begun in March 1302 under the supervision of priets Richard de Wynepol and Henry de Graundeston with help from the architect, Master James of St George In September 1302. \n \n Sixty men and 140 women helped dig the ditches; the men were paid twopence and the women a penny daily. One hundred foot-soldiers were still employed as labourers on the castle in November and work continued during the Summer of 1303. \n \n In September 1313, Linlithgow Peel was retaken for Scotland by an ordinary Scot named William Binning or Bunnock who was in the habit of selling hay to the garrison of the peel. \n  When the gate was opened for him, he halted his wagon so that it could not be closed, his eight compatriots leapt out from their hiding place under the hay, and they captured the peel for King Robert the Bruce. King Robert sent reinforcements and had the peel dismantled so that it could not be retaken by the English. \n \n In 1424, the town of Linlithgow was partially destroyed in a great fire. King James I started the rebuilding of the Palace as a grand residence for Scottish royalty, also beginning the rebuilding of the Church of St Michael immediately to the south of the palace: the earlier church had been used as a storeroom during Edward\'s occupation. Over the following century the palace developed into a formal courtyard structure, with significant additions by James III and James IV.</string>

    <string name="william_wallace_monument">William Wallace Monument</string>
    <string name="WALdesc">Stirling’s famous landmark stands above the fields where William Wallace led his troops to victory at The Battle of Stirling Bridge, and tells the story of the patriot and martyr who became Scotland’s National Hero \n \n  Over 700 years ago, tyranny and terror were the tools being used by England to rule Scotland. Occupied and oppressed, the Scottish nation sought a hero to challenge the cruelty of King Edward I. \n \n When the two countries faced each other at The Battle of Stirling Bridge in 1297, Scotland was led to victory by a figure destined to become a national hero – William Wallace. Wallace had a burning desire for peace and freedom which united the country’s clans, gained the loyalty of its people, struck fear into his enemies and defied the cruel hand of an evil, warring and invading king. \n \n Stirling was the main entry point to the north of Scotland, and it was here, that Wallace was encamped with his army.  The bridge (which was just upstream from the 15th century stone bridge that still stands today) was only wide enough for two horsemen to pass abreast, and on the 11th September the battle began as the English were forced to cross the bridge. \n \n Wallace and Andrew de Moray waited until more than half the English had made the crossing before springing their trap.  Scottish spearsmen charged down the causeway.  Those on the right flank forced their way along the river bank to the north end of the bridge, preventing the English from escaping. Those of the English army who survived the battle, including Warenne, retreated to Berwick. \n \n After his betrayal and capture, Wallace was taken to London, where he was tried.  He was found guilty, and cruelly executed on 23rd August 1305.  His death did not end Scotland’s Wars of Independence, and Robert the Bruce continued the fight, achieving victory at the Battle of Bannockburn in 1314. \n \n Over the years further elements were added to the Monument, including the Wallace Sword.  This impressive two-handed sword was first recorded in Dumbarton Castle in 1505. </string>

    <string name="sandwoodbaybeach">Sandwood Bay Beach</string>
    <string name="SANDdesc"> Reputedly the most beautiful beach in Britain, the wild and spectacular Sandwood Bay in Kinlochbervie is backed by huge sand dunes and a loch. \n \n Facing straight into the teeth of the North Atlantic, the beach has nearly 1.5 miles of wide pink sand which is flanked by cliffs. To the south stands the impressive sea stack of Am Buachaille, while behind the bay’s large dunes stretches Sandwood Loch - a freshwater loch full of brown trout and a great place to fish. The beach is considered to be one of the most unspoilt beaches in the whole of mainland Britain. \n \n This remote bay has no road access but can be reached by a 4 mile, well-trodden and fairly flat path leading from the gravel car park at the hamlet of Blairmore. \n \n The name Sandwood Bay probably derives from the Viking name \'Sandvatn\' ("sand water") and it is believed longboats were dragged across the sands into Sandwood Loch. \n \n There are also remains of Pictish settlement in the area. The area has been largely uninhabited since 1847 when the land was cleared for sheep farming as part of the Highland Clearances. A number of shepherds huts remained and were occasionally occupied until around 1940. \n \n On 30 September 1941, Sergeant Michael Kilburn from 124 Squadron at RAF Castletown was flying a Spitfire south west of Cape Wrath when the engine failed. He crash-landed the plane on the beach at Sandwood, and managed to escape uninjured. The wreck remained on the beach and over time the entire bodywork was eroded away by the sea but its engine, a Rolls Royce Merlin, remains largely intact and occasionally emerges into full view whenever tidal and weather conditions permit.</string>

    <string name="cullen">Cullen Beach</string>
    <string name="CULLENdesc">Cullen Beach is an attractive sandy beach with excellent water quality and plenty of space for you to relax and sunbathe or get up and play beach volleyball. \n \n  Cullen Beach is a wide expanse of golden sand and is one of the most stunning beaches in all of Scotland. This beach has more to offer than just the beach, it is a great location to be outdoors doing other activities. \n \n The beach sits in front of Cullen Golf Course and there are plenty of coastal walks and trails to follow. Cullen Bay is well sheltered by the surrounding cliffs and moray dolphins are often spotted from the beach and bay. \n \n most magnificent of all as you come down the hill from the town is Cullen Bay with the isolated sea stacks known as the \'Three Kings\', which rise up from the sands. \n \n They are said to be grave markers of 3 Norse Kings who died at the Battle of Bauds in 962 ~ The first mention of Cullen in Scottish history was in 962 when King Indulf was killed by the Norwegians (and/or Danes) at the mouth of the river Cullen and referred to as the Battle of the Bauds  \n \n "Atween Coedlich and the sea, There lies Kings\' sons three."  Legend has it that within the vicinity, a Scots, Danish and a Norwegian King are buried, marked by the three isolated rocks within Cullen Bay and named the "Three Kings". <br /> <br /> There is free car parking underneath the viaduct with facilities beside the golf clubhouse. There are plenty of shops in Cullen town centre, however in the summer months the beach is often serviced by an ice cream van.</string>

    <string name="luskentyre">Luskentyre Sands</string>
    <string name="LUSKdesc">Luskentyre sands is found on the west coast of South Harris in the Outer Hebrides. \n \n Luskentyre is one of the largest and most spectacular beaches on Harris. Named one of the UK’s best beaches in the TripAdvisor Travellers’ Choice Awards, Luskentyre sands boasts miles of white sand and stunning green-blue water.\n \n Scenery includes wonderful sand dunes and the island of Taransay, famous for being the setting of the BBC’s Castaway. Nearby activities include hillwalking, cycling and much more. \n \n The name Luskentyre derives from Lios-cinn-tir, meaning \'headland fort\', although there is no trace or local knowledge of a fort at the headland. However, the headland contains the site of an old part of Luskentyre Cemetery. \n \n Luskentyre Beach has been voted Britain\'s best beach with no surprise there at all. \n \n  Wildlife in the area includes the common scoter, the velvet scoter, the Eider duck, the wigeon, the long-tailed duck, the red-breasted merganser, the great northern diver and the Slavonian grebe. \n \n Luskentyre is accessible from the A859, via a minor road.</string>

    <string name="westsands">West Sands Beach</string>
    <string name="WSBdesc"> St Andrews West Sands is located on the eastern coastline of the Kingdom of Fife. The sea at the beach was also known as the "water of eden" \n \n The 2-mile-long beach is adjacent to the famous St Andrews Links golf course. Sand dunes on the beach, which have long protected the golf course, are themselves in danger of eroding away, and are the subject of a restoration project. \n \n Famous for the opening scenes of the film Chariots of Fire.  This scene was reenacted during the 2012 Olympics torch relay,  The beach was also featured in the 2012 Summer Olympics Opening Ceremony \n \n As for the golf course; According to the earliest surviving document from 1552, the "playing at golf" on the links adjacent to the "water of eden" was granted permission by Archbishop Hamilton. The course which dates back to medieval times, is an Open Championship course – which was first staged in 1873. \n \n If you\'re looking for something to do after the beach, around the corner there is also St Andrews Castle situated on cliff-tops. The castle was first erected around 1200 as the residence, prison and fortress of the bishops of the diocese. Several reconstructions occurred in subsequent centuries, most notably due to damage incurred in the Wars of Scottish Independence.</string>

    <string name="lochness">Loch Ness</string>
    <string name="LOCHdesc">Loch Ness is a large, deep, freshwater loch in the Scottish Highlands extending for approximately 37 kilometres southwest of Inverness. Its surface is 16 metres above sea level. \n \n Loch Ness is best known for alleged sightings of the cryptozoological Loch Ness Monster, also known affectionately as "Nessie". From time to time they offer boat rides across the loch to look for "Nessie". \n \n  Loch Ness is the second-largest Scottish loch by surface area after Loch Lomond, but due to its great depth, it is the largest by volume in the British Isles. \n \n Its deepest point is 230 metres (126 fathoms; 755 feet) making it the second deepest loch in Scotland after Loch Morar. A 2016 survey claimed to have discovered a crevice extending to a depth of 271 m (889 ft), but further research determined this to be a sonar anomaly. \n \n It contains more water than all the lakes in England and Wales combined, and is the largest body of water in the Great Glen, which runs from Inverness in the north to Fort William in the south. \n \n  Right next to the loch is Urquhart Castle. \n The present ruins date from the 13th to the 16th centuries, though built on the site of an early medieval fortification. Founded in the 13th century, Urquhart played a role in the Wars of Scottish Independence in the 14th century. It was subsequently held as a royal castle, and was raided on several occasions by the MacDonald Earls of Ross.</string>

    <string name="bennevis">Ben Nevis</string>
    <string name="BENdesc">Ben Nevis is the highest mountain in the British Isles, situated in Inverness-shire in the Highlands of Scotland. The summit is 1,345 metres (4,413 ft) above sea level.\n \n Ben Nevis stands at the western end of the Grampian Mountains in the region of Lochaber, close to the town of Fort William. The summit is the highest land in any direction for 459 miles (739 km). \n \n The mountain is a popular destination, attracting an estimated 100,000 ascents a year, around three-quarters of which use the Donkey Track from Glen Nevis. \n \n The 700-metre (2,300 ft) cliffs of the north face are among the highest in Scotland, providing classic scrambles and rock climbs of all difficulties for climbers and mountaineers. They are also the principal locations in Scotland for ice climbing. \n \n The summit, which is the collapsed dome of an ancient volcano, features the ruins of an observatory which was continuously staffed between 1883 and 1904. \n \n Ben Nevis\'s summit has hit temperature highs of 7.1 and temperature lows of -2.8 degrees celsius. </string>

    <string name="smoo">Smoo Cave</string>
    <string name="SMOOdesc">Smoo Cave is a large combined sea cave and freshwater cave in Durness in Sutherland, Highland, Scotland. The cave name is thought to originate from the Norse "smjugg" or "smuga", meaning a hole or hiding-place. \n \n The cave is unique within the UK in that the first chamber has been formed by the action of the sea, whereas the inner chambers are freshwater passages, formed from rainwater dissolving the carbonate dolomites. \n \n Partway through the cave the waters of Allt Smoo also drop in as a 20 metres (66 ft) high waterfall. This is mainly due to the nearby dolomite - quartzite geological boundary where the Allt Smoo stream crosses the impermeable quartzites and sinks on meeting the permeable dolomites. \n \n The cave is located 2 kilometres (1.2 mi) east of the village of Durness and is presently served by a car park, toilets, stairs and walkways. \n \n Plans are being considered for access improvements for the estimated 40,000 visitors it receives annually. Tours of the cave also operate during the summer, taking visitors to the inner chamber by boat. </string>

    <string name="strathclyde">Strathclyde Country Park</string>
    <string name="STRATHdesc">Strathclyde Country Park is a country park located on the outskirts of Motherwell in North Lanarkshire, Scotland. \n \n It is located next to the River Clyde between Hamilton and Motherwell. Strathclyde Park forms what used to be known as the Low parks of the now demolished Hamilton Palace, and still includes buildings associated with the palace. When the loch was created in the early 1970s it involved the flooding of the old mining village of Bothwellhaugh. \n \n The park offers many amenities and attractions such as coarse angling, woodland walks, watersports, and a camping and caravanning site. \n \n One of Scotland\'s theme parks, M&amp;D\'s, is located in the park and up until 1996, the music festival T in the Park was held here. \n \n The remains of Bothwellhaugh Roman Fort and a Roman bathhouse can be seen in the park, where the South Calder Water flows into the loch. There is an arched Roman bridge across the South Calder nearby. The site of the Battle of Bothwell Bridge (1679) is to the north west of the park.</string>

    <string name="favourites_fragment">Favourites Fragment</string>
    <string name="home_fragment">Home Fragment</string>
    <string name="map_fragment">Map Fragment</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>

    <string name="infotitle">About Immersive Scotland</string>
    <string name="infotext">Immersive Scotland was created by "Dylan Castle". \n \n The idea behind this project was to connect and immerse everybody back in to normal life in Scotland, post COVID-19. \n \n This app will help you discover the best it has to offer from History and Nature all the way to stunning Beaches. This app will cater an experience for everyone throughout the whole country. \n \n This app will give you more than just a location to visit, it will provide you will knowledge and insight in to the background of all the destinations, and provide you with a virtual guide tour to really enhance your experience with information, pictures, videos and audio clips. \n \n FEEDBACK &amp; REVIEWS \n \n For all feedback comments and reviews about the app please forward them to 1704363@rgu.ac.uk</string>
    <string name="delete_account">Delete Account</string>
    <string name="night_mode">Night Mode   </string>
    <string name="notifcations">Notifcations</string>
    <string name="settings">SETTINGS</string>
    <string name="map_key">map_key</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="locationsettings">Location</string>
    <string name="favourite_locations">Favourite Locations</string>
    <string name="is">Immersive Scotland</string>
    <string name="take_a_trip_back_in_time">Take a trip back in time!</string>
    <string name="explore_the_beaches">Explore The Beaches!</string>
    <string name="discover_nature_s_beauty">Discover Nature\'s Beauty</string>
    <string name="dylan_castle">Dylan Castle</string>
    <string name="_1704363_rgu_ac_uk">1704363@rgu.ac.uk</string>
    <string name="categories">Categories</string>
    <string name="favourites">Favourites</string>
    <string name="map">Map</string>
    <string name="account">Account</string>
    <string name="settings_item">Settings</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="log_out">Log-Out</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign-Up</string>
    <string name="location1">Location</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="dunnottar_castle">Dunnottar Castle</string>
    <string name="prince_alberts_pyramid">Prince Alberts Pyramid</string>

    <string-array name="programming_languages">
        <item>Cullen</item>
        <item>Luskentyre</item>
        <item>Sandwood Bay Beach</item>
        <item>WestSands Beach</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="description">
        <item>Lovely beach \n in Cullen</item>
        <item>Stunning beach in Luskentyre</item>
        <item>Great beach at Sutherland</item>
        <item>Gorgeous Beach in Fife</item>
    </string-array>



</resources>

